<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Said Jomaa</title>
    <link>https://SaidJomaa.github.io/Said_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Said Jomaa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://SaidJomaa.github.io/Said_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Likelihood and Severity of Road Accidents In Victoria</title>
      <link>https://SaidJomaa.github.io/Said_Portfolio/post/predicting-likelihood-and-severity-of-road-accidents-in-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SaidJomaa.github.io/Said_Portfolio/post/predicting-likelihood-and-severity-of-road-accidents-in-victoria/</guid>
      <description>The study focuses on predicting accident severity and identifying key contributing variables using road accident data from Victoria, Australia (2006-2020).
Multiple logistic regression is employed to determine influential variables and develop an accident prediction approach.
Preprocessing techniques, such as outlier handling, addressing missing values, and data transformation, are applied.
The final model, based on undersampled data, achieves an accuracy prediction power of 76.6% and identifies speed zone, road surface conditions, light conditions, urbanization status, and safety equipment usage as significant factors in severe accidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbine Investment Analysis</title>
      <link>https://SaidJomaa.github.io/Said_Portfolio/post/wind-turbine-investment-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://SaidJomaa.github.io/Said_Portfolio/post/wind-turbine-investment-analysis/</guid>
      <description>The project involved analyzing primary datasets and external sources to assess the U.S. wind turbine market for a clean energy private equity firm.
Data cleaning was performed using Python and pandas, including splitting tables, handling null values, and fixing invalid codes.
The analysis uncovered insights about the global and U.S. wind power market, highlighting growth trends and the concentration of wind turbine plants in the Midwest.
Factors such as turbine size, location, and operator efficiency were associated with power generation and revenue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
